DEVARAJ DHARMENDRA

National Diploma in Quantity Surveying (NVQ 5) Address: 199, Sea Street, Negombo, Sri Lanka.

Phone: +94 77 50 200 29

Email: devdharma93@gmail.com **Date of Birth:** 11th of March, 1993

EXECUTIVE PROFILE

Accomplished, result driven, Quantity Surveyor, gaining over 2 years of experience working in Sri Lanka. During the course of the above period, I have gained extensive experience and familiarity with the following documents. I have also gained extensive experience from the various projects I handled which involves foreign projects in the Middle East Region viz **Qatar, United Arab Emirates and Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.**

- ✓ ICTAD Conditions of contract
- ✓ Building Schedules of Rates (BSR)
- ✓ New Rules of Measurements (NRM2)
- ✓ Standard Method of Measurements (SMM7)
- Principles of Measurement International (POMI)
- ✓ Qatar standard method of measurements (QSMM)
- ✓ Sri Lankan Standard Method of Measurement (SLS 573)
- ✓ Civil Engineering Standard Method of Measurement (CESMM3 and 4)

Currently, I'm following the **Bachelor degree in Quantity Surveying** at **University of Vocational Technology - Ratmalana**.

I am a student member of the Institute of Quantity Surveyors Sri Lanka too.

KEY EXPERIENCE / SKILLS

- ✓ Preparation of Civil and <u>MEP BOQs</u> for tendering purposes, preparation of cost plans and estimates, taking off measurements based on various "Standard Methods of Measurements".
- ✓ Knowledge and experience in Commercial and Residential buildings, Villas, Metro line, Highways, MEP works.
- ✓ Knowledge and experience in Pre Contract Quantity Surveying functions.
- ✓ Languages well versed in: English, Sinhala and Tamil.
- ✓ Sound computer literacy including;
 - AutoCAD
 - Cost X
 - MS Office packages

- Plan swift 9
- CATO suite (CAUSEWAY)
- CAD Measure (CAUSEWAY)

PROFESSIONAL HISTORY

<u>YEAR</u>	<u>POSITION</u>	<u>COMPANY</u>
January 2015 - August 2015	Trainee Quantity Surveyor	P&C Professional Quantity Surveyors and Cost Consultants (Pvt) Ltd, Sri Lanka.
August 2015 - March 2017	Junior Quantity Surveyor	P&C Professional Quantity Surveyors and Cost Consultants (Pvt) Ltd, Sri Lanka.

EMPLOYMENT PORTFOLIO

P&C PROFESSIONAL QUANTITY SURVEYOR & COST CONSULTANTS (PVT) LTD

Minuwangoda, Sri Lanka.

Position: Junior Quantity Surveyor Period: January 2015 to March 2017

Major Duties & Responsibilities:

- ✓ I was responsible for preparation of cost plans in various stage of design development.
- ✓ I prepared quantity take-off sheets and sent query sheet to the designers in order to clarify any identified discrepancies in design drawings with the given project specifications.
- ✓ I have prepared Bills of Quantities for Structural and Architectural works in various country projects in according to the Standard Methods of Measurement.
- ✓ Preparation of MEP Bills of Quantities for various elements such as Mechanical, Electrical, and Plumbing Systems.
- ✓ I have prepared Infrastructure take-off sheets and Bills of Quantities using CESMM3 for Road works, Bridges and Utility networks, Landscaping and external works.

I have involved in the following projects as a Quantity Surveyor and carried out Pre Contract Quantity Surveying functions.

Last Project - Providing Service for Faithful & Gould (F & G)

Riyadh metro project is one of a major ongoing project of Saudi Arabia. Ar Riyadh Development Authority (ARD) is the client of this project. The project consist of 180km metro line, 07 numbers of deports, 87 numbers of stations. The total cost of the project is \$26 billion. My major responsibility as a Quantity Surveyor for all the Pre Contract Quantity Surveying and preparing Bills of Quantities, Measurement based on - CESMM3 / POMI, Software used CATO suite (CAUSEWAY), CAD Measure (CAUSEWAY), Revit Architecture.

Project based on New Rules of Measurements (NRM2)

→ Project: Qatar Foundation Education City Health & Wellness Facilities

Client - Ghassan Ahmed Al-Suliman Furnishing Trading Co.Ltd

Project based on Standard Method of Measurements (SMM7)

→ **Project:** Altair Residential Project Colombo, Srilanka

Client - Indocean Developers (Private) Limited

Projects based on Civil Engineering Standard Method of Measurement (CESMM3)

→ **Project:** Development of North Al Wathba Infrastructure

Client - Musanada

→ **Project:** Roads & Infrastructure in Al Themaid and Rawdat Egdaim (MMUP - Phase 3, Package 18)

Client - Public Work Authority, Qatar

Project based on Qatar Standard Method of Measurements (QSMM)

→ **Project:** Doha Oasis Theme Park

Client - Halul Real Estate Investment Company

Projects based on Principles of Measurement International (POMI)

→ **Project:** Company Package - 8, Staff Accommodations at Oman Convention and Exhibition Centre, Muscat, Sultanate of Oman

Client - Oman Tourism Development Co SAOC

→ Project: Al Badia Heights Villas, Dubai

Client - Dubai Festival City LLC

→ **Project:** Suites in the Skai, Dubai

Client - Skai Holdings

→ **Project:** One at Palm Jumeirah Dubai

Client - Imperial Residencies Limited

→ Project: MBR Dubai Hills - Phase 03

Client - Emaar Properties PJSC

→ Project: NFPC Mega Plant, Abu Dhabi - Kizad

Client - Abu Dhabi Ports Company

→ **Project:** City land Mall, Development of Wadi Al Safa 4

Client - Global Village (LCC)

→ Project: IKEA Building, Bahrain

Client - Ghassan Ahmed Al-Suliman Furnishing Trading Co.Ltd

→ Project: SEEF Residential package, Lusail

Client - Lusail Real Estate Development Company

→ **Project:** Proposed Commercial Development (3B+G+M+28+P) for Alfardan Properties at COM-13, Lusail, Doha, State of Qatar.

Client - Alfardan Properties

- → **Project:** DIP Automotive Development, Phase 1 CJD & HONDA New Showroom & Service Centers
- → **Project:** DIP Automotive Development, Phase 2 Dubai Investment Park (Lexus Showroom)

 Client Al Futtaim Real Estate Co LCC
- → **Project:** Jumeirah living at marina gate

Client - The Select Group

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

Bachelor of Technology in Quantity Surveying

University of Vocational Technology - (UNIVOTEC) (Currently, following this degree programme)

National Diploma in Quantity Surveying (NVQ Level - 5)

Vocational Training Authority of Sri Lanka

Diploma in Computer Science

Golden Key Institute of Information Technology

Certificate in MEP Quantity Surveying

CADD Centre Lanka

Certificate in Computer Aided Drafting and Modeling (AutoCAD)

The Open University of Sri Lanka (Faculty of Engineering Technology)

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

G.C.E Advance Level Examination in 2012 - Mathematics stream G.C.E Ordinary Level Examination in 2009

D.S.Senanayake College, Colombo - 7

NON-RELATED REFEREES

Mrs. Chulika Dasanayake
B.Sc (Hons) QS, MRICS, AAIQS, AIQSSL
Executive Director/Chief Operating Officer
P&C Professional Quantity Surveyor and
Cost Consultants (Pvt) Ltd

No: 68, Airport Road, Minuwangoda,

Srilanka.

Mobile: 071-9900830

Land: 011-2281966 / Fax: 011-2281966

Email: pandcpqscc@gmail.com

J. Thilak Thanuja Mendis
B.Sc (Hons), M.Sc, MBA, LCGI, ICIOB,
ACIArb, AMIIESL

Former Managing Quantity Surveyor, P&C Professional Quantity Surveyor and

Cost Consultants (Pvt) Ltd

No. 68, Airport Road, Minuwangoda,

Srilanka.

Mobile: 071-4714364

Email: thilakmendis@yahoo.com

I do hereby certify that the above information is true and accurate to the best of my knowledge.

Date:

D.Dharmendra Signature of the Applicant